

sunilkumarsheoran@gmail.com +1-6043674432

linkedin.com/in/sunilkumarsheoran

ECS 412, University of Victoria, Victoria, BC, Canada. V8P 5C2

I am a second-year master's student at the University of Victoria with 3 years of full-stack software development work experience. I am seeking full-time opportunities to use my skills for the organization's success and learn new skills in cutting-edge technologies being used in the industry.

#### **Education**

### M.Sc. in Computer Science

Expected Dec 2020

University of Victoria, BC, Canada.

**Thesis**: Deep Reinforcement Learning in games in self-play settings.

**B.Tech. in Information Technology** May 2014 NIT Durgapur, West Bengal, India.

#### **Technical Skills**

- **Languages**: Java, Python, JavaScript, SQL, C/C++, HTML5, Golang.
- Tools & Frameworks: Git, PyTorch, REST, JSON, Google Web Toolkit (GWT), JDBC, Hibernate, Electron, AngularJS, Excel, JasperReports, Docker, Kubernetes, gRPC.
- Concepts: OOPs, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Agile practices, Deep Learning.
- Operating Systems: Windows and Linux.

# **Experience**

#### Teaching Assistantship / University of Victoria, Victoria, Canada.

Jan 2019 – Aug 2020

• Conducted labs, exams and marked assignments for 300 level computer science courses(Database systems and Digital Logic).

# Technical Associate / Zillious Solutions, New Delhi, India.

July 2018 - Dec 2018

- Developed a scalable workaround for size limitation of java enums with minimal changes in the application.
- Added support for customizable vouchers and integrated multiple payment gateways, including Razorpay, Paytm, etc.
- Integrated a pre-developed machine learning model into the application for finding duplicate hotels. Decreased the time for marking duplicate hotels by 90% in live search results for hotels.

#### Software Developer / Drishti-Soft Solutions, Gurugram, India.

June 2014 - Sep 2016

- Awarded with Excellence Award 2016 and won /tmp 2014 a 10 days 24x7 coding event.
- Majorly worked on Ameyo Report, a GWT based front-end, and Jasper based backend; the work includes a new UI, backend enhancements, and automating the generation of *Transformers*, a data de-normalization component, by using EMF modeling.
- Increased performance for a major customer's database server by 90% using table partition and multicolumn indexes.
- Increased performance of a statics managing component by 60% using soft references based cache for reflective calls.
- Developed a context-aware report designer with the Front-end based on GWT with data populating based on Eclipse Modeling Framework (EMF) model instances and outputs a proprietary file format (.drxml), which converted by the backend into a JasperReports based object. It was used to give demos to international customers as a future project.
- Created Magic Numbers: Predicts hardware requirements (CPU, RAM, and HDD) based on customer functional requirements.
- Created a report scheduler based on the Quartz library with support for centralized reporting and graphical reports.
- Delivered components for the automation of the collection process for an major Indian Bank. Implemented a fresh UI,
  Integrating Hitachi Content Platform (HCP) for report storage, created a custom SSO authentication server & various domain-specific features like Centralized Exclusion.
- Interviewed candidates, prepared questions, and did the training for new employees for the 2016 and 2017 hiring seasons.

### Software Developer Intern / Morphing Machines, Bangalore, India.

June 2013 - Aug 2013

 Designed and developed the front-end interface for a research project called 'Development of A Flexible Framework for A Network On Chip'. Research paper link - git.io/Jen9l.

# **Projects**

- **DOTA2 win prediction** (git.io/JvB5P): Fetch the data using Steam API, then did data transformation (one-hot encoding, etc.) and applied nine different machine learning algorithms (Logistic Regression, Ada Boost, etc.) to predict the winning team.
- Matchmaking for online multiplayer games (git.io/JenE4): Created and deployed a working demo for ten-player deathmatch matchmaking server using docker images deployed on a single Kubernetes cluster on Google Cloud Platform and then analyzed the system using Grafana and Prometheus services.
- DQN agent for Coinrun (git.io/JvB5r): Implemented DQN and DoubleDQN algorithms from scratch to play the Coinrun game.
- College Study Point Website: A web portal where students can upload documents and comment on them.